# Mohamed Adel Rezk, B.Sc., M.Sc in Management Information Systems.

7th Cherry Park, Newcastle, Galway, Ireland Tel: +353899676871 E-mail: moh.adelrezk@gmail.com

#### AREAS OF STRENGTH

- Semantic web technologies "Web 3.0"
- Web services and APIs developing
- E-commerce and back office operations
- System Analysis and Design
- Technology development and deployment
- Data Warehousing
- Business Process Engineering

- Project Management
- Networking Standards
- Software Engineering Lifecycle
- Object Oriented Architecture
- Java, C#, PHP, RDF, XML, OWL, SPARQL development
- Location Based Services

#### **E**DUCATION

- 2017, M.Sc. in Management Information Systems, with specialization in Government Data Analysis from Alexandria University, Egypt and cosupervision from National University of Ireland Galway.
- 2010, B.Sc. in Management Information Systems, with specialization in Semantic Web Applications from Alexandria University, Egypt.

# ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS

- B.Sc. degree awarded with "Distinction Class of Honor" and ranked top of 2010 Class.
- Graduation Project title:

"Enhancing Internet User's Experience using Semantic Web Technologies Enhanca Application"

Awarded "Best Bachelor Graduation project in academic year 2009/2010" by "CSS –Computer Scientific Society, Egypt"

# **C**URRENT **P**OSITIONS

- Research Assistant at eGov Unit, Insight Centre, National University of Ireland.
- January 2015 Present, Galway, Ireland.
- Co-Founder at Tedux.com.
- September 2010 Present, Alexandria, Egypt.

#### Personal Details

- Date and Place of Birth: 24<sup>th</sup> December 1988, Alexandria, Egypt.
- Residency: Stamp 4, Ireland.
- Martial status: Married, 2 Daughters.
- Military Obligatory Service: Completed in September 2012, Egypt.

# **P**ROJECTS

#### OGI

Feb'16 - Feb'18

http://www.opengovintelligence.eu/ Open Government LOSD Analysis

and Design.

#### **YDS**

December'15- December'17
<a href="https://yourdatastories.eu/">https://yourdatastories.eu/</a>
Open Government Data

Handling.

#### **RTPA**

March'15- March'17
<a href="http://routetopa.eu/">http://routetopa.eu/</a>
Open Government Data
Anomaly Detection.

# **Social Repository of Ireland**

Jan'15 - June'15

http://www.dri.ie/projects/ Social Media Data Analysis. **Newswire 2.0** 

Sept'15- Sept'16

Social Media Data Analysis.

**GOV-DAF** 

March'15- August'17

https://github.com/mohadelr

ezk/GOV-DAF Masters Thesis

**Flatorenta** 

Aug'09 – Oct'09 Supervisor. **Enhanca** 

Jan'10 – Aug'10 Bachelor Thesis. Fady Ya Asta

Jan'14- Aug'14 Supervisor

# **T**RAINING

# **Deep learning**

Workshop
Insight Centre, DCU,

Dublin.

27-28 April'17

**Scientific Conferences organization** 

Workshop

International Board of Certified Trainers European Division (IBCT)

15-16 Sep'14

**Scientific Research** 

Workshop

DAAD organization

23 Jun' 13

Java Programming
Advanced

Oracle Certified,

Information Technology

Institute

In Feb'13

#### .Net Framework

Workshop

I.S.C Department, AU

In Aug'10

#### Web developing and designing

Training diploma

Information Technology Club, AU

Jul'09 - Sep'09

**English Language** 

Advanced

AMIDEAST Dec '09 – Jan'09 **Java Programming** 

Intermediate

C.S.C

Apr'09 - May'09

# **R**EFRENCES

# Dr. Adegboyega Ojo, PhD, MSc.

Senior Research Fellow and the E-Government Group Leader.

E-Government Unit, Insight centre for Data Analytics,

National University of Ireland, Galway, Ireland.

Phone: (353) 91-495336

Email: adegboyega.ojo@insight-centre.org

# • Prof. Dr. Ghada El khayat, PhD, MSc.

Professor of Information Systems and the Department Head.

Department of Information Systems and Computers,

Faculty of Commerce, Alexandria University, Alexandria, Egypt.

Phone:(02) 01009991121 Email: hadaek@gmail.com

•Others are Available upon request, also check my publications co-authors.

# **E**XPERIENCE **S**UMMARY

# Information Systems and Computers department, Faculty of Commerce, Alexandria University

May 2011 - Present

#### Teaching and Research Assistant.

Researching in the Semantic Web field, teaching Labs of Information Systems courses and supervising students' graduation projects(i.e. Systems Analysis and Design, OOP, ECommerce, DB Design and Artificial Intelligence).

Alexandria, Egypt

# Information and Communication Technology Project (ICTP) - Alexandria University

November 2010 - May 2011

### **Oracle Application Support Specialist.**

Administrating and Maintaining the University M.I.S Applications .

Alexandria, Egypt

#### **Bibliotheca Alexandrina**

March 2009 - January 2011

# Volunteer at Bibliotheca Alexandrina Planetarium Science Center [PSC].

Organization of many events in the BA.

Alexandria, Egypt

#### **New Jersey Dunkin' Donuts**

August 2009 - October 2009

Trainee.

Sales department.

Great experience of how business is done in the states .

Elizabeth, New Jersey, United States of America

#### Alexandria petroleum company

June 2008 - July 2008

Trainee.

Human resources department.

Auditing department.

Import and Export departments.

Alexandria, Egypt

#### **British Council Egypt**

August 2004 – August 2006

#### Volunteer In Dreams + Teams Program.

Future Leaders preparing program.

Organization of many events in Egypt and 21 other Countries.

Cairo, Egypt

# **Egyptian Armed Forces, Western district**

#### July 2011 – September 2012

#### Information Technology Specialist.

Responsible for all I.T related tasks needed during the military operations .

Squad of the western district command center.
Also awarded the certificate of excellent solider.

Marsa Matrouh, Egypt

# Information Systems and Computers department, Faculty of Commerce, Alexandria University

January 2010 - August 2010

Working on my graduation project titled:

"Enhancing Internet User's Experience using Semantic web technologies " .

Alexandria, Egypt

#### **Egyptian Stock Exchange Market**

August 2006 - Present

Trader.

Alexandria, Egypt

#### **National Societe General Bank**

July 2009 - August 2009

Trainee .

Credit and Loans departments.

Sales department.

Customers service department.

Alexandria, Egypt

#### Pachin [for paints and chemicals]

In August 2006

Trainee .

Import and Export department.

Alexandria, Egypt

#### **Students' Union**

In 1998 - In 2004 - In 2005

President of the union in both Elementary and

Preparatory schools.

President of the Social committee in High school.

Alexandria, Egypt

# SKILLS And COMPETENCES

# Academic awards, honors, fellowships, additional D. New Jersey Dunkin' Donuts courses:

- A. Scientific Research Workshop by DAAD organization-June 23rd 2013.
- B. Java programming certificate that I acquired by attending an Oracle University training course -In February 2013 - Certificate available-.
- C. .NetFramework Workshop I.S.C Department, Alexandria University - In August 2010.
- D. Photoshop, Dreamweaver and Adobe flash through a web developing training course I carried out available-.
- 2009 to January 2009 Certificate available-.
- F. Java Programming Intermediate C.S.C, Egypt -From April 2009 to May 2009 -Certificate available-.

# Social skills and competences:

Through my previous years of education I always have been eager to maintain a Good communication skills, willingness to work as a part of a team, eagerness to learn new languages and to contact with other cultures.

And the following positions and their supporting certificates confirm my positive actions.

- A. Students' Union In 1998 -In 2004 -In 2005 President of the union in both Elementary and Preparatory Schools. President of Social Committee in High School.
- B. British Council Egypt August 2004 - August 2006 Volunteer In Dreams + Teams Program. Leaders preparing program. Organization of many events in Egypt and 21 other Countries.
- C. Bibliotheca Alexandrina March 2009 – January 2011 Volunteer at Bibliotheca Alexandrina-Planetarium Science Center [PSC]. Organization of many events in the BA.

August 2009 -October 2009 Trainee .

Sales department.

Great experience of how business is done in the states.

Elizabeth, New Jersey, United States of America.

# Organizational skills and competences:

I have four major work experiences including my current positions, through them I faced a lot of From July 2009 to September 2009 - Certificate situations and tasks that made my leadership and my sense of organization to develop and mature.

- E. English Language AMIDEAST From December A. First job is Oracle applications support specialist that included the tasks of Administrating and Maintaining the Alexandria University M.I.S. Applications as a part of 11 colleagues we were responsible for every faculty at the university we managed those tasks and shared our information in a great manner that made our directors relaxed all the time.
  - Second job is Information Technology Specialist during my military service at the Egyptian Armed Forces I was responsible for all Information Technology related tasks needed during the military operations at Squad of the western district command center I also awarded the certificate of excellent solider for my achievements in upgrading and updating the Squad's Information Technology Infrastructure and Software and managing a team of 9 soldiers to achieve this task.
  - C. Third job is Teaching and Research assistant at **Information Systems and Computers** department, Faculty of Commerce, Alexandria University in which I am Performing research in the Semantic Web field with my Researchers colleagues, teaching laboratories of Information Systems courses and supervising students' graduation projects in addition to helping them to learn how to manage their teams technically and socially,

# SKILLS And COMPETENCES cont.

I also have other managerial tasks such as: 1- ICT in our lives Annual Scientific conference other committees and Administrating the conference's submission website.

http://ictinourlives.alexu.edu.eg/

# 2- Quality Assurance Unite

Preparing Surveys to Assure the deferent aspects of educational quality in the faculty of commerce.

#### 3- Examination Control

Controlling and managing the examination processes for faculty students.

D. Fourth and last one is Co-Founder at Tedux.com, this job includes an execution of all my gained knowledge and experiences through my education, research, personal interests, and previous work experience specially entrepreneurship and leadership, we at Tedux.com manage to maintain a dynamic work environment with innovation all over the place, to demonstrate this I will list what we do at Tedux.com:

#### ■ In-house Research Lab

We are so curious and always keep our hands dirty by researching, discovering and working to make new useful things or to add and/or anneal to something that already exists. Our areas of interests include:

- Semantic Web (e.g. Ontology Engineering, Linked Open Data, SPARQL, HTML5, Javascript, and **Enhancing the Arabic Content).**
- ➤ B-SEO (e.g. Rdfa, Schema.org, Microformats, Interactive Solutions, Touch Screens, and Motion Detection).

**≻Linux**.

#### ■Web Development

We provide cost-effective solutions using the latest standards in web programming including (HTML5 based Web Applications - Facebook Pages and Applications – Open Source based Solutions (e.g. Magento, Wordpress, Drupal, Moodle and many other Open Source solutions).

#### Mobile Development

Custom entertaining mobile apps development in all platforms including

(HTML5 based Mobile Web development - Native Development - Android Development - BlackBerry Heading the Media and PR committee, member in Development - iOS Development - Windows Mobile Development).

#### **Technical skills and competences:**

- A. Writing information systems laboratory tutorial sheets specially for both Systems Analysis and Design course (e.g. CASE tools tutorials for OpenModelSphere and Draw.io), and Artificial Intelligence and Decisions Support Systems course (e.g. genetic learning, fuzzy logic and Heuristics) as a part of my career as a teaching and research assistant at Alexandria University.
- B. Very good knowledge and experience in using Web Services specially those related to Semantic web as a kind of knowledge extraction using web crawled data (for instance Alchemy and WordNet) and my Bachelor graduation project titled: "Enhancing internet user experience using semantic web technology".

Awarded" Best Graduation project" by CSS – Computer Scientific Society, Egypt; is a very good evidence for my knowledge.

- Wide hands on experience in networks installation gained through my military service period that I spent it as Information Technology Specialist responsible for all I.T related tasks needed during the military operations. At Squad of the western district command center. Also awarded the certificate of excellent solider that proves my dedication and devotion to my work.
- D. Versed in maintaining Oracle database servers and in managing and administrating the applications built over it due to my work experience as an Oracle Application Support Specialist for Alexandria University Applications.
- Wide experience in Stock market as I worked as a stock broker, and enrolled in trading training program at my college - I attached the certificateand I also own stocks and make trades now and then till now based on my previous experiences I accumulated.

# SKILLS And COMPETENCES cont.

- F. Good experience of the quality and maturity of **Subjects studied for my degrees that are relevant** businesses running in the U.S.A. as I traveled there and trained for short period in Dunkin Donuts. There I learned the different methods and tools that big chain businesses use in order to maintain identical quality of the service at all branches.
- G. Versed in most of the latest banking processes and aiding software, as I was trained in National Socitee General Bank (NSGB), Egypt.
- H. Finally, I have a good knowledge of importing and exporting processes that I gained while training in both Pachine for paints and chemicals, and Alexandria for petroleum companies both located in Egypt but operating overseas.

# **Computer skills and competences:**

- A. APIs, Web Services, SMS gateway, CSS, JS, Jquery, MySQL, Cpanel and open office through project Flatorenta I managed with my undergraduate colleges in summer vacation.
- B. CASE tools( OpenModel Sphere, draw.io and MYSQL workbench), XML, RDF, SPARQL, PHP, Jason, APIs, Semantic web frame works, Paython, Ruby-Go, Csandra, UML, DFD and Microsoft office through my bachelor graduation out of 3000 students in all majors of faculty of project and my current career as Research and Teaching Assistant.
- C. Photoshop, Dreamweaver and Adobe flash through a web developing training course I carried out - Certificate attached-.
- D. Java programming certificate that I acquired by attending an Oracle University training course -Certificate attached-.

#### **Language Skills and Competences:**

My current career as a teaching and research assistant is carried out in English language. In addition, the master degree I am enrolled in is also taught in English.

Furthermore, my B.Sc is mostly taught in English. Moreover, I have GRE and TOEFL ITP scores.

# to this application:

#### A. B.Sc subjects

Programming Java and C# (Introduction and Advanced), Database Management and Data warehouse(Introduction and Advanced), Artificial Intelligence, Decision Support Systems, Quantitative Analysis, Systems Analysis and Design, Networks, Graduation Project(Semantic Web), E-Commerce.

# B. M.Sc. subjects

Applied Statistics, Data Structure using Java, Software Engineering, Decision Support Systems and Intelligent Systems, Cloud Computing, Advanced Database design, and Advanced topics in Information Systems (big data related topics).

# Titles of projects completed

Github repo.

https://github.com/mohadelrezk

#### **Academic Achievements**

# MSc., and B.Sc. in Management Information Systems

#### **Overall marks**

("4781" out of "5700")

#### Ranking

(Ranked 1st out of 120 students majored in Management Information Systems, and ranked 15th commerce, Alexandria University, Egypt Class 2010).

Finally, I played various sports as I am a member of the sports club next to my home, this made it uncomplicated to enroll in amateur and professional teams of the following sports: Basketball, Football, volleyball, Handball, Navy Scout and Cycling If you recruited me I will let you win some.

#### **P**ublications

#### **Published:**

 "A Government Decision Analytics Framework Based on Citizen Opinion"

In: 9th International Conference on Theory and Practice of Electronic Government 2016 (ICEGOV2016).

Authors: Mohamed Adel Rezk, Adegboyega Ojo, Ghada A. El khayat, and Safaa Hussein.

Link: https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=2910093.

Venue: Montevideo, Uruguay — March 01 - 03, 2016.

**Organizers:** United Nations University Operating Unit on Policy-Driven Electronic Governance (UNU- • EGOV).

 "A Proposed Government Decision Support System Based on Citizens Interactions over Social (PRO-VE 2017). Networks"

In: 5th International Conference on Information and Hatem Bensta and Adegboyega Ojo. Communication Technology in our lives 2016 (ICT2016).

Authors: Mohamed Adel Rezk, Adegboyega Ojo, Ghada A. El khayat, and Safaa Hussein.

Venue: Faculty of Commerce, Alexandria University Alexandria, Egypt December 19 th -21st, 2015.

**Organizers:** Information Systems and Computers Department, Faculty of Commerce, Alexandria University.

 "Towards A Vocabulary for Open Public Policy" [poster]

In: 10th International Conference on Theory and Practice of Electronic Government 2017 (ICEGOV2017).

Authors: Mohamed Adel Rezk, Mahmoud H. Aliyu, Hatem Bensta and Adegboyega Ojo.

Venue: India — March 07 - 09, 2017.

**Organizers:** United Nations University Operating Unit on Policy-Driven Electronic Governance (UNU-EGOV).

 "A Government Decision Analytics Framework Based on Citizen Opinion: Elaboration of the Knowledge Base Component"

In: 6th International Conference on Information and Communication Technology in our lives 2017 (ICT2017).

Authors: Mohamed Adel Rezk, Adegboyega Ojo, Ghada A. El khayat, and Safaa Hussein.

Venue: Faculty of Commerce, Alexandria University Alexandria, Egypt December 17th 19th, 2016. **Organizers**: Information Systems and Computers Department, Faculty of Commerce, Alexandria University.

#### In press:

"Standardising Public Policy Documentation to Foster Collaboration Across Governmental Agencies"

In: 18th IFIP Working Conference in virtual Enerprise

Authors: Mohamed Adel Rezk, Mahmoud H. Aliyu,

Venue: Venizia, Italy 18 th 20th 2017.

Organizers: International Federation for Information Processing

 "MiningGovernmentalCollaborationthrough Semantic Profiling of Open Data Catalogues and Publishers"

In: 18th IFIP Working Conference in virtual Enerprise (PRO-VE 2017).

Authors: Mohamed Adel Rezk, Adegboyega Ojo, Islam Ahmed hassan.

Venue: Venizia, Italy 18 th 20th 2017.

Organizers: International Federation for Information Processing.

# **Project Deliverables:**

- "The Open Gov Intelligence project" D3.1, D3.2. Co- Author.
- "NewsWire2.0" Co- Author.
- "Social Repository of Ireland" <u>D-5</u>, <u>D-7</u>. Co- Author.